const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",t="accounting",o=200,i=120,a=[{id:474,question:"The total of the trial balance is",option:{a:"N 6 600",b:"N 6 650",c:"N 5 600",d:"N 5 900"},section:"Given: Returns inwards [N1, 500]; Cash [N1, 550]; Discount received [N2, 850]; Capital [N3, 800 ]; Debtors [N900];	Sundry expenses [  ?  ]; 	The value of sundry expenses is 150% of returns inwards plus 50% of debtors.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:167,question:"The difference between book keeping and accounting is that while",option:{a:"book keeping interprets data accounting records it",b:"book keeping is regarded as  the language of the business, accounting ascertains its .strength and weakness",c:"book keeping records data accounting interprets it",d:"book keeping - summaries information, accounting communicates it."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:382,question:"Which of the following information is recorded in the returns outwards book?",option:{a:"Goods purchased on credit and subsequently returned to supplier",b:"Fixed asset bought on credit and subsequently returned to supplier",c:"Cash payment received from a customer and subsequently returned to supplier",d:"Goods sold to a customer and subsequently returned to the business."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:170,question:"The yearly depreciation using the straight line method would be",option:{a:"N5,200",b:"N6,500",c:"N8, 800",d:"N4, 400"},section:"Use the information below to answer the question that follows. A machine bought for N 35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of N= 9, 000. ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:392,question:"The accounting principle that is applied to check arbitrary actions on the part of accountants is",option:{a:"consistency",b:"materiality",c:"objectivity",d:"realization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:15,question:"Money spent on buying of plots of land by a firm is ",option:{a:"Capital Expenditure ",b:"capital receipts ",c:"Revenue Expenditure",d:" Revenue Receipts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:214,question:"The depreciation method in which the number of years of the useful life of an asset is allocated in a reverse order is",option:{a:"straight line",b:"reducing balance",c:"sum of the years’ digits",d:"revaluation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:278,question:"Which of the following is not an input device?",option:{a:"Card reader",b:"Paper top reader",c:"Alpha-numeric keyboard",d:"Line printer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:466,question:"Find the value of the total assets?",option:{a:"N 17 700",b:"N 10,500",c:"N 20,000",d:"N 15,400."},section:"Use the information below to answer question: Net loss [N2,300]; Capital [N10,500]; Liabilities [N7, 200]",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following is a spreadsheet application?",option:{a:"Excel",b:"Word",c:"Internet",d:"Windows"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:103,question:"The accounting principle that states that, in the preparation of accounting statement, revenue are recognized as        soon as goods are passed on to the customer is the",option:{a:"materiality concept.",b:"matching concept.",c:"consistency concept.",d:"realization concept."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:344,question:"The quality of output information depends on the",option:{a:"quality of input data",b:"time of processing",c:"speed of processing",d:"quantity of output device"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:262,question:"A fixed asset fully written-down by a trader is now considered to be worth N5,000. The double entry required to effect       this is: debit",option:{a:"Asset Account; credit Purchases Account.",b:"Asset Account; credit Capital Account.",c:"Capital Account; credit Asset Account.",d:"Capital Account; credit Profit and Loss Account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:342,question:"Which of the following is found on the credit side of a partnership’s appropriation of profit account?",option:{a:"Interest on capital",b:"Interest on drawings",c:"share of profit",d:"Drawings"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:368,question:"When an asset is sold, the entries for the accumulated depreciation are: debit",option:{a:"Asset Disposal Account; credit Provision for Depreciation Account.",b:"Provision for Depreciation Account; Credit Asset Disposal Account",c:"Fixed Asset Account; Credit Asset Disposal Account",d:"Asset Disposal Account; Credit Fixed Asset Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:58,question:"If a business shows a debit balance in its own record of its bank balance, this indicates.",option:{a:"The business has a bank overdraft",b:"The business is a debtor of the bank",c:"The business has money in the bank",d:"The ledger entry must be wrong."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:111,question:"Which of the following is not an item on the credit side of the purchases ledger control account?",option:{a:"Cash received",b:"Cash payment",c:"Contra settlement",d:"Cheque payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:8,question:"At the end of a trading period, wages will be  ",option:{a:"debited to trading account and shown as a current liability ",b:"credited to profit and loss Account and shown as a current liability ",c:"credited to trading account and shown as a current asset ",d:"debited to profit and loss account and shown as a current liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:97,question:"A business is treated as being separate from the owners. This statement is emphasized by",option:{a:"consistency concept.",b:"realization concept.",c:"going concern concept.",d:"business entity concept."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:366,question:"The cost of sales is",option:{a:"GHc/  2,160,000t",b:"GHc/ 1440,000",c:"GHc/ 1,080,000",d:"GHc/  720,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer question: The total sales of a business was GHc/ 2,160,000. The average mark-up for the year was 50%.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:273,question:"Which of the following is not prepared by a partnership?",option:{a:"Trading Account",b:"Profit and Loss Account",c:"Income and Expenditure Account",d:"Profit and Loss Appropriation Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:341,question:"Which of the following relates to cash basis of accounting?",option:{a:"Accruals and prepayments are considered",b:"Debtors and creditors are recorded",c:"Fixed assets are written off in the year of purchase",d:"Profits are maximized"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:108,question:"The Public Accounts Committee is an organ of",option:{a:"military regime.",b:"parliament.",c:"presidency.",d:"councilors."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:371,question:"The accounting concept underlying the treatment of personal expenses of the business owner as drawing is",option:{a:"periodicity",b:"accrual",c:"entity",d:"materiality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:441,question:"Expenses paid during the conversion of a partnership to a 	company are",option:{a:"debited to the partners’ capital account",b:"debited to the realization account",c:"debited to the cash account.",d:"credited to the realization account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:345,question:"The source document used to make entries in the purchases day book is",option:{a:"debit note",b:"credit note",c:"invoice",d:"receipt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:423,question:"On dissolution, the final distribution of cash to partners is based on",option:{a:"partnership agreement",b:"Articles of Association",c:"goodwill",d:"capital balances."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:234,question:"Revenue is recognized in the profit and loss account as soon as a",option:{a:"debtor pays what is due from him",b:"sale of goods takes place and money is received",c:"sale of goods takes place whether or not money is received",d:"sale of a fixed asset takes place."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:101,question:"The minimum number of persons required to form a partnership business is",option:{a:"2.",b:"3.",c:"5",d:"10."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:194,question:"An item is fictitious because it",option:{a:"does not exist",b:"is too costly",c:"is worthless",d:"cannot be sold for cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:398,question:"The imprest account is subsidiary to the",option:{a:"ledger account",b:"bank account",c:"cash book",d:"petty cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:361,question:"Which of the following accounts would appear in the nominal ledger?  (I)  Sanison’s account (a debtor)  ( II) Motor vehicle account (III) Sales account  (IV)  Rent and rates account",option:{a:"I, II and III only",b:"I, III and IV only",c:"II, III and IV only",d:"Ill and IV only"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:261,question:"Which of the following is not a source document?",option:{a:"Journal proper",b:"Sales invoice",c:"Debit note",d:"Credit note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:163,question:"An increase in government expenditure within a year is taken care of by means of",option:{a:"virement",b:"financial regulations",c:"supplementary estimate",d:"warrant."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:195,question:"Which of the following is not a personal account?",option:{a:"Bolaji Account",b:"Drawings Account",c:"P.Z. Plc Account",d:"Cash Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:188,question:"A financial plan of action expressed in monetary terms is known as",option:{a:"imprest",b:"consolidated fund",c:"warrant",d:"budget"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:376,question:"The accounting ratio used to measure the average number of days for which suppliers remain unpaid is",option:{a:"stock turnover",b:"creditors’ payment period",c:"debtors collection period",d:"return on capital employed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:499,question:"What is the net profit?",option:{a:"N  46,000",b:"N 45,000",c:"N  28,000",d:"N  27,000"},section:"Use the information to answer questions: Work-in-progress 1/1[N 1,000 ];	Work-in-progress 31/12 	[N 2,000 ]; Production cost of goods manufactured 	[N 20,000 ] Sales [N 50,000]; Stock of finished goods 1/1 [N 4,000 ]; Stock of finished goods 31/12 [N 5,000 ]; Selling and distribution expenses[  N 2,000 ]; Administrative expenses [ 1,000 ]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:155,question:"The trader’s capital in a single entry system is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"gross profit",b:"statement of affairs",c:"suspense account",d:"appropriation account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:50,question:"At the end the fiscal year, account receivable has a balance of 100,000 and allowance for doubtful account has a balance of 7,000. The expected that realized value of the  receivable is: account",option:{a:"N 107,000",b:"N100,000",c:"c. N93,000",d:"N 147,000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:53,question:"A debit may signify: ",option:{a:"an increase in the owner's capital amount",b:"an increase in a liability account",c:"a decrease in an asset account",d:"an increase in an asset account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:11,question:"The journal is a book ",option:{a:"of primary entry into which all transactions are entered before posting ",b:"kept by journalist for reporting events ",c:"of prime entry into which postings are made from the ledger  ",d:"of analyzing major accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:463,question:"The provision for bad debt is",option:{a:"N2 000",b:"N 800",c:"N3 000",d:"N1 900."},section:"Use the information below to answer question: Debtors [N20 000]; Provision for bad debts 10%; Provision for discount on debtors 5%.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:286,question:"Capital expenditure for the year was",option:{a:"Le 545,000",b:"Le 490,000",c:"Le 450,000",d:"Le 300,000"},section:"The Health Department of Zango Local Government incurred the following expenditure in 2010. Construction of hospital wards [ Le 300,000 ]; Purchase of hospital beds [ Le  40,000 ]; Salaries and wages  [ Le 80,000]; Purchase of drugs  [ Le 55,000]; Purchase of X-ray machine [ Le 150,000]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:416,question:"In the balance sheet, the subscription in arrears will be",option:{a:"N 200",b:"N 300",c:"N 1,200",d:"N 1,300"},section:"On January 1, 2000, a club’s assets and liabilities were as follows: Club house [ N8,000 ]; Subscription in arrears [ N300]; Cash [N1,000]; Wages owed [N100]. The club has 50 members and annual subscription is N 100 per member. Subscription received is N 4,000 and this includes 1999 arrears of  N 200.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:316,question:"Which of the following expresses the accounting equating?",option:{a:"Capital + Assets = Liabilities",b:"Assets - Liabilities = Capital",c:"Liabilities + Current Assets = Fixed Assets",d:"Liabilities - Capital = Current Assets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:467,question:"What will be the equity of the business?",option:{a:"N 12,800",b:"N 4,900",c:"N 8,200",d:"N 9,500."},section:"Use the information below to answer question: Net loss [N2,300]; Capital [N10,500]; Liabilities [N7, 200]",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:512,question:"Replacement and renewal of fixed assets are",option:{a:"revenue receipt",b:"capital receipt",c:"capital expenditure",d:"revenue expenditure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:211,question:"Which of the following serves the same purpose as a Trading Account?",option:{a:"Branch Adjustment Account",b:"Goods sent to Branch Account",c:"Branch Stock Account",d:"Branch Debtors Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:332,question:"Which of the following is not stated in the partnership agreement?",option:{a:"Profit sharing ratio",b:"Interest on capital",c:"Interest on fixed asset",d:"Purpose of partnership"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:4,question:"Which   of the   following   is   a  long  term liability ",option:{a:"bank overdraft ",b:"bank deposit ",c:"good will ",d:"debentures"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:114,question:"The process of detecting, tracing and eliminating errors in a computer program is",option:{a:"reproduction.",b:"debugging.",c:"sorting.",d:"retrieving."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:51,question:"Which of the following accounts would be classified as a current on the balance sheet?",option:{a:"Office Equipment",b:"Accumulated Depreciation",c:"Land",d:"Accounts receivable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:149,question:"A discount that is allowed to encourage a debtor to pay off his debt within a period is the",option:{a:"trade discount",b:"annual discount",c:"periodic discount",d:"cash discount."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:510,question:"The book value per share is obtained by dividing",option:{a:"shareholders equity by outstanding shares",b:"total assets by outstanding shares",c:"gross profit by outstanding shares",d:"net profit by outstanding shares"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:501,question:"What is the accumulated fund?",option:{a:"23,700",b:"27,750",c:"29,650",d:"51,650"},section:"Given: Furniture and fittings [N 20,000]  Equipment [N15,000] Bank overdrafts [ N6,500] Bar creditors [ N4,800 ] Subscription in arrears [ N4,700 ] Subscription in advance [ N650]",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:23,question:"Bad debt is also known as ",option:{a:"Unpaid debt",b:"irrecoverable debt  ",c:"Payment debt  ",d:"current    debt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:135,question:"The documents that provide instant information to firms on their transactions with banks are",option:{a:"bank statement and debit note",b:"cheque stub and deposit slip",c:"cheque book and cashbook",d:"payslip and credit invoice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:300,question:"The liability is",option:{a:"D7,580",b:"D6,580",c:"D5,380",d:"D1,000"},section:"Use the following information to answer questions:: Cash in hand	[D 1,440]; Cash at Bank [D 2,440]; Stock [D 2,500]; Furniture and fittings [D 2,200]; Creditors [D 1,000]",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:245,question:"Using the straight line method, the depreciation charged for year 2002 was",option:{a:"N 160,000",b:"N  130.000",c:"N  100,000",d:"N  60,000"},section:"Motor vehicles (at cost) 1/1/2002   [N1,000,000],  Addition to motor vehicles 1/7/2003  [N  600,000] 	Depreciation rate 10%",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:72,question:"A business shows total debtors' balance of N400,000 in its ledger at the end of its financial customer owing N40,00 are bankrupt, and there is no  possibility of getting the debt paid. A further 2% of the debt is considered doubtful. What debtor’ total will be included as a current asset in the balance sheet? ",option:{a:"N400,000  ",b:"N352,800  ",c:"N352, 000  ",d:"N36, 200"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:205,question:"Where there are no proper books of account, the capital at the commencement of a period is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"Total Debtors and Creditors Accounts",b:"Bank Reconciliation Statement",c:"Statement of Affairs",d:"Trading, Profit and Loss Accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:67,question:"Which of these items would be accounted for as an expense? ",option:{a:"repayment of a bank loan ",b:"dividends to stockholders ",c:"the purchase of land ",d:"payment of the current period's rent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:417,question:"Where the debit side of the income and expenditure account is higher than the credit side, the difference is",option:{a:"deficit",b:"surplus",c:"gain",d:"loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:185,question:"In Manufacturing Account, prime cost plus factory overhead is known as",option:{a:"conversion cost",b:"cost of raw materials consumed",c:"total cost",d:"production cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:492,question:"What is the value of closing stock using simple average?",option:{a:"N 11,500",b:"N 17,000",c:"N 17,500",d:"N 28,500"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Jan. 1 Received 1,000 units at   N 10 each; Jan. 2 Received 2,000 units at   N  12 each; Jan. 3 Issued 1,500 units; Jan. 4 Received 1,000 units at   N  11 eac; Jan. 5 Issued 1000 units",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:451,question:"The lighting charge to be apportioned to Zema is",option:{a:"N 891",b:"N 819",c:"N 927",d:"N 975"},section:"Lighting [N2, 925]; Rent [ N2, 640]; Salary [N4, 050] The expenses are for three different products: Zema, Zeta and Zera. They are apportioned on the basis of production. 4500 units of the products are produced, out of which 1260 and 2060 units are for Zema and Zeta respectively.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:295,question:"An underwriter for a company’s share is paid",option:{a:"Interest.",b:"commission.",c:"dividend.",d:"salary."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:142,question:"A proprietor started business with N13, 000.  Assets and liabilities at the end of the year; fixed assets N8, 800, stock N2, 600, debtors  N1 , 000, cash N3, 000 and creditors N1 , 000. Determine the profit for the year?",option:{a:"N2, 400",b:"N3, 000",c:"N9, 800",d:"N 1 , 400"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:337,question:"Which of the following expenses is allocated according to the floor 	area?",option:{a:"Wages and Salaries",b:"Rent and rates",c:"Canteen expenses",d:"Discount allowed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:153,question:"The total cash and cheques received from customers in a control account is derived from the",option:{a:"income and expenditure account",b:"cashbook",c:"purchases day book",d:"sales journal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:479,question:"Musa, a prepaid customer of XYZ and KLM, bought  N1500 recharge card from XYZ and  N2000 recharge card from KLM for business calls. The entry to record these transaction is debit",option:{a:"telephone  N 3,500, credit XYZ and KLM  N 3,500",b:"telephone N 3,500. credit cash  N 3,500",c:"sundries N 3,500, credit KLM  N 3,500",d:"sundries  N 3.500, credit telephone  N3,500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:312,question:"What is the ledger entry for the sale of plant and machinery on credit to Wilson?",option:{a:"Credit Sales Account and debit Cash Account",b:"Credit Plant and Machinery Account and debit Wilson’s Account",c:"Credit Sales Account and debit Wilson’s Account",d:"Credit Plant and Machinery Account and debit Cash Account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:159,question:"When stock is withdrawn, for personal use, the accounting entries is to debit",option:{a:"stock account, credit drawings",b:"drawing account credit stock account",c:"personal account credit cash account",d:"cash account, credit personal account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:438,question:"I.Profits and losses will be shared unequally II.  Interest is not allowed on capital, III. Salaries are not allowed. IV. Interest is charged on drawings. Which of  the following would apply where there is no agreement during partnership formation?",option:{a:"I only",b:"I, II and III",c:"I, II and IV",d:"II and III."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:41,question:'Wilson Company owns land which cost 14100, 000. If a "quick sate" of the land was necessary to generate cash, the company feels it would receive only N80, 000.    The company continues to report the asset on the balance sheet at N100, 000   This is justified under which of the following concepts?  ',option:{a:"The historical-cost principle.",b:"The value is tied to objective and verifiable past transactions.",c:"Neither of the above.",d:' Both "a" and "b"'},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:502,question:"I.  Space occupied by each department    II. Average value of stock held by each department III. 	Departmental turnover  IV. Number of articles sold by each department. From the information given, the two most logical bases for apportioning expenses that are common to departments are",option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and III",c:"II and III",d:"Ill and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:91,question:"The returns on capital employed is",option:{a:"17.2%",b:"16.2%.",c:"15.2%.",d:"11.2%."},section:"Use the following information to answer question. Net profit [ 60,000], Total Assets [ 520,000], Current liabilities [ 150,000], Current assets[ 280,000] ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:309,question:"Which of the following is a real account?",option:{a:"Plant account",b:"Salaries account",c:"Creditors account",d:"Trading account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:7,question:"A debit balance on a bank statement indicates that ",option:{a:"bank is a debtor to the customer ",b:"customer is a debtor to the bank ",c:"bank is not a creditor to the customer ",d:"customer is not a debtor to the bank"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:118,question:"The prime cost is",option:{a:"GHc 64,500.",b:"GHc 64,000.",c:"GHc 58,500.",d:"GHc 52,500."},section:"Use the following information to answer question:  Stock of raw materials 1/1/09  [ 5,000 ], Stock of raw materials 31/12/09   [ 5,500], Purchase of raw materials [ 50,000], Carriage inwards [3,000], Direct labour [ 12,000], Factory overhead [17,500]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:174,question:"To correct an error, the Purchases Account was debited while Suspense Account was credited. Which  of  the following was the cause of the error?",option:{a:"Under casting of purchases",b:"Overcasting of purchases",c:"Original entry.",d:"Transportation of returns outwards"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:439,question:"The value of goods sent to branch is",option:{a:"N 4 000",b:"N 6000",c:"N 8000",d:"N 2000"},section:"Use the information below to answer questions: Stock (1/1/02) at selling price [N2, 000 ]; Goods sent to branch (selling price)    [  ?  ]; Sales by branch (selling price)   [4, 500 ]; Stock (31/12/02)   [  	?    ] Opening stock is 1/4 of goods sent to branch.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:266,question:"which of the following is a Trading Account item?",option:{a:"Discounts allowed",b:"Discounts received",c:"Carriage outwards",d:"Carriage inwards"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:327,question:"The accounting concept that allows the cost of kitchen cutlery to be expensed, though it will be used for more than one year is",option:{a:"materiality",b:"accrual",c:"going concern",d:"business entity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:246,question:"Using the reducing balance method, the depreciation charged for year 2002 was",option:{a:"N 100,000",b:"N  90,000",c:"N  80,000",d:"N  60,000"},section:"Motor vehicles (at cost) 1/1/2002   [N1,000,000],  Addition to motor vehicles 1/7/2003  [N  600,000] 	Depreciation rate 10%",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:80,question:"The distinguishing feature between a two-column and three-columncash book is",option:{a:"discount column",b:"cash column",c:"bank column",d:"ledger folio"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:79,question:"…………………checks the arithmetical accuracy of double entry accounts ",option:{a:"trading account ",b:"profit and loss account ",c:"balance sheet ",d:"trial lance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:488,question:"Determine the capital of the business",option:{a:"N 9,400",b:"N 6,000",c:"N 3,400",d:"N 3,000"},section:"Use the information to answer question: Total current assets [N2,000 ]; Total fixed assets [N 4,000 ]; Current liabilities [N 1,200 ]; Drawings [N 200 ]; Long-term loan 	[N 2,000 ]",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:17,question:"Final accounts of (i) Cash book (ii) trading account  (iii) Profit and  loss account  (iv)Balance sheet  ",option:{a:"i only ",b:"i and ii only",c:"iii and iv only ",d:"ii and iii  only"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:504,question:"Which of the following is a common cause of a discrepancy between head office and branch trial balance?",option:{a:"Debtors and cash in transit",b:"Creditors and cash in transit",c:"Stock and cash in transit",d:"Stock and prepayments"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:202,question:"The person, who is responsible for the formation of a company is called the",option:{a:"promoter",b:"sponsor",c:"shareholder",d:"director"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:346,question:"book that contains individual accounts of suppliers is the",option:{a:"purchases ledger",b:"general ledger",c:"nominal ledger",d:"sales ledger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:203,question:"The amount of a company’s profit given to a shareholder is known as",option:{a:"premium",b:"dividend",c:"interest",d:"allotment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:370,question:"In a not - for - profit making organization, when the total income 	is less than the total expenditure, the difference is a",option:{a:"surplus",b:"shortfall",c:"loss",d:"deficit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:437,question:"Purchases of raw materials amount to N  81 000, direct labour is N  38 000 and factory overhead N  29 000. Calculate the prime cost.",option:{a:"N 176,000",b:"N 170,000",c:"N 167,000",d:"N  156,000."},section:"Stock at start: Raw materials [N57, 000]; Work-in-progress [42, 000]; Finished goods [71, 000 ]",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:472,question:"The fourth stage of the accounting information system is",option:{a:"recording",b:"interpreting",c:"summarizing",d:"classifying."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:320,question:"Which of the following is not a method of depreciating fixed assets?",option:{a:"Revaluation",b:"Straight line",c:"Diminishing balance",d:"Obsolescence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:112,question:"When a business is purchased from a sole trader, the excess of the purchase price over the net assets is",option:{a:"reserve.",b:"goodwill.",c:"freehold.",d:"valuation price."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:148,question:"When the fixed capital method is used, the partners share of profits and remunerations are credited to the",option:{a:"current account.",b:"profit and Loss account.",c:"profit and loss appropriation account.",d:"capital account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:196,question:"A provision is",option:{a:"an expense of business to be paid for in cash",b:"an amount of loss from trading activities",c:"a loss in value of all business assets",d:"an expense the amount of which is not certain"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:200,question:"An expense becomes an accrual because it",option:{a:"is due for payment",b:"is a Profit and Loss Account item",c:"is a Trading Account item",d:"is to be paid within the next one year"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:69,question:"A debit balance of Nl50,000 in a cash account   shows   that   ",option:{a:"  cash  has   been overspent   by   N150,000   ",b:"  there   was N150,000 cash in hand ",c:" the total of cash received   was   less   than   N150,000   ",d:"N150,000 was the total of cash paid out. "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:268,question:"Capital receipt is collected",option:{a:"on sales of motor vehicle.",b:"on sales of stock in trade.",c:"from trade debtor",d:"from trading activities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:383,question:"Calculate the stock figure to be included in the balance sheet at the year end.",option:{a:"D408,000",b:"D346,000",c:"D284,000",d:"D62,000"},section:" Use the following information to answer question: Branch stock account (at selling price)  D346,000 - debit Branch mark-up account D62,000 - debit",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:71,question:" On December 31, 2012, Infinite Grace had a note payable due on August 1, 2013. On January 20, 2013, Infinite Grace signed a financing agreement to borrow the balance of the note payable from a lending institution to refinance the note. The agreement does not expire within one year, and no violation of any provision in the financing agreement exists. On  February 1, 2013. Infinite Grace was informed by its financial advisor that the lender is not expected to be financially capable of honouring the agreement. Infinite Grace's financial statements were issued on March 31, 2013. How should Infinite Grace classify the note on its balance sheet at December 31,2012? ",option:{a:"as a current liability because the financing agreement was signed after the balance sheet datecapable of honouring the agreement   ",b:"as a current liability because the leader is not expected to be financially ",c:" as   a   long-term   liability because  the agreement  does   not  expire within one year ",d:" as a long-term liability because no violation of any provision in the financing agreement exists."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:306,question:"Purchase invoice is first entered in the",option:{a:"purchases account",b:"cash book",c:"sales journal",d:"purchase journal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:169,question:"If the scrap value is now N15, 000, what will be the yearly depreciation using straight line method?",option:{a:"N11 000",b:"N7, 000",c:"N 4, 000",d:"N24. 000"},section:"Use the information below to answer the question that follows. A machine bought for N 35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of N= 9, 000. ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:274,question:"A partner who only makes capital contribution but does not take part in the management of the partnership business is a/an",option:{a:"ordinary partner",b:"limited partner",c:"dormant partner",d:"nominal partner"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:212,question:"Which of the following is not a revenue receipt?",option:{a:"Receipt from sales of goods",b:"Rent from premises sublet",c:"Interest on savings account",d:"cash on sale of fixed asset"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:157,question:"Clifford pays rent of  N200 per month for premises. He paid N 2,800 within the year, Compute the prepayment.",option:{a:"N300",b:"N400",c:"N660",d:"N200"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:329,question:"The accounting concept that states that a firm’s financial affairs must be separated from that of the owner’s private transactions is",option:{a:"business entity",b:"going concern",c:"consistency",d:"duality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:187,question:"Where a business is purchased, the full amount of the purchase consideration is credited to",option:{a:"Purchase of Business Account",b:"Creditor’s Account",c:"Vendor’s Account",d:"Purchaser’s Account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1997"},{id:218,question:"A sales ledger contains",option:{a:"creditors’ accounts",b:"nominal accounts",c:"real accounts",d:"debtors’ accounts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2006"},{id:350,question:"The accounting treatment for a dishonoured cheque is; debit",option:{a:"Customer’s Account; Credit Bank Account",b:"Bank Account; Credit Customer’s Account",c:"Customer’s Account; Credit Sales Account",d:"Sales Account; Credit Customer’s Account\\"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:281,question:"The portion of authorized capital that has been allotted to subscribers is",option:{a:"called up capital",b:"paid up capital.",c:"issued capital",d:"nominal capital."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:429,question:"Debentures can be redeemed out of",option:{a:"existing share capital reserve",b:"existing general reserve",c:"proceeds from new issue of shares",d:"withholding tax."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:46,question:"If the equipment account has a balance of N22.500 and its accumulated account has a balance of N14,000 the book value of the equipment is:  ",option:{a:"N22.500   ",b:"N8.500 ",c:"N 14,000  ",d:"N36.500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:6,question:"Which of the following is the most liquid ",option:{a:"stock ",b:"debtors ",c:"machinery ",d:"loose tools"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:86,question:"A dishonoured cheque is",option:{a:"debited in the cash book.",b:"credited in the cash book.",c:"double entry in the cash book.",d:"credited in the bank book."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"}],n={message:e,subject:t,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,t as subject,i as total};
